<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
     xmlns:jalbum="http://jalbum.net/jalbumrss">
    <channel>
        <title>Фримовые - Phrymaceae</title>
   	<link>../../..</link>
        <generator>jAlbum 31.1</generator>
   		<description>Phrymaceae, also known as the lopseed family, is a small family of flowering plants in the order Lamiales. It has a nearly cosmopolitan distribution, but is concentrated in two centers of diversity, one in Australia, the other in western North America. Members of this family occur in diverse habitats, including deserts, river banks and mountains.
Phrymaceae is a family of mostly herbs and a few subshrubs, bearing tubular, bilaterally symmetric flowers. They can be annuals or perennials. Some of the Australian genera are aquatic or semiaquatic. One of these, Glossostigma, is among the smallest of flowering plants, larger than the aquatic Lemna but similar in size to the terrestrial Lepuropetalon. The smallest members of Phrymaceae are only a few centimeters long, while the largest are woody shrubs to 4 m tall. The floral structure of Phrymaceae is variable, to such an extent that a morphological assessment is difficult. Reproduction is also variable, being brought about by different mating systems which may be sexual or asexual, and may involve outcrossing, self-fertilization, or mixed mating. Some are pollinated by insects, others by hummingbirds. The most common fruit type in this family is a dehiscent capsule containing numerous seeds, but exceptions exist such as an achene, in Phryma leptostachya, or a berry-like fruit in Leucocarpus.
About 16 species are in cultivation. They are known horticulturally as &quot;Mimulus&quot; and were formerly placed in the genus Mimulus when it was defined broadly to include about 150 species. Mimulus, as a botanical name, rather than a common name or horticultural name, now represents a genus of only seven species. Most of its former species have been transferred to Diplacus or Erythranthe. Six of the horticultural species are of special importance. These are Diplacus aurantiacus, Diplacus puniceus, Erythranthe cardinalis, Erythranthe guttata, Erythranthe lutea, and Erythranthe cuprea.
Phrymaceae has recently become a model system for evolutionary studies.
Within the order Lamiales, Phrymaceae is a member of an unnamed clade of five families. Two of these families, Mazaceae and Rehmanniaceae are not part of the APG III system. They were not formally validated until 2011.</description>
        <jalbum:absolutePath>https://herbariuminfo.netlify.app/%D0%94%D0%B2%D1%83%D0%B4%D0%BE%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%BD%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Dicotyledones/%D0%AF%D1%81%D0%BD%D0%BE%D1%82%D0%BA%D0%BE%D1%86%D0%B2%D0%B5%D1%82%D0%BD%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Lamiales/%D0%A4%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BC%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Phrymaceae/</jalbum:absolutePath>
    	<jalbum:link rel="sub" href="https://herbariuminfo.netlify.app/%D0%94%D0%B2%D1%83%D0%B4%D0%BE%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%BD%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Dicotyledones/%D0%AF%D1%81%D0%BD%D0%BE%D1%82%D0%BA%D0%BE%D1%86%D0%B2%D0%B5%D1%82%D0%BD%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Lamiales/%D0%A4%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BC%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Phrymaceae/%D0%93%D1%83%D0%B1%D0%B0%D1%81%D1%82%D0%B8%D0%BA%20%D0%BA%D1%80%D0%B0%D0%BF%D1%87%D0%B0%D1%82%D1%8B%D0%B8%20-%20Mimulus%20guttatus/album.rss" title="Губастик крапчатый - Mimulus guttatus" thumbnail="https://herbariuminfo.netlify.app/%D0%94%D0%B2%D1%83%D0%B4%D0%BE%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%BD%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Dicotyledones/%D0%AF%D1%81%D0%BD%D0%BE%D1%82%D0%BA%D0%BE%D1%86%D0%B2%D0%B5%D1%82%D0%BD%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Lamiales/%D0%A4%D1%80%D0%B8%D0%BC%D0%BE%D0%B2%D1%8B%D0%B5%20-%20Phrymaceae/%D0%93%D1%83%D0%B1%D0%B0%D1%81%D1%82%D0%B8%D0%BA%20%D0%BA%D1%80%D0%B0%D0%BF%D1%87%D0%B0%D1%82%D1%8B%D0%B8%20-%20Mimulus%20guttatus/thumbs/DSC04508.webp" thumbnailWidth="512" thumbnailHeight="410" />
    </channel>
</rss>
